ETHAN CLOIN

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT 904-910-9435 dev.ethancloin@gmail.com https://github.com/ethancloin Jacksonville, FL SKILLS Python3 (FastAPI and SQLAlchemy)

Java (Android and Spring)

JavaScript (React and Vue)

TypeScript (Express and Sequelize)

HTML5 + CSS (MaterialUI and Bootstrap)

Git / GitHub

Databases (MySQL, SQLite)

REST Interfaces

TOOLS

Postman

Visual Studio Code / PyCharm

Android Studio

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

University of North Florida

2018-2021

ABET Accredited

PROFILE

Motivated developer with a professional background in several programming languages and paradigms. Experience working in the **payment** and restaurant technology industries.

Strong written and verbal **communication** skills, focused on digesting technical problems to convey in a non-technical manner. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, and **collaborate** as part of a productive team.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Pax Technology

Sep 2022 - Present

- Contributed to fullstack, cross-platform mobile application, including support for various payment processors and methods.
 - Vue.js, Cordova, Java
- Contributed to Android library allowing users to submit feedback on Pax Android
 applications.
 - Android Studio, Java
- Quickly absorbed industry knowledge to develop PCI (Payment Card Industry) Compliant applications.
- Collaborated with multiple teams within the organization to deliver solutions in a timely manner

Software Support

Hazlnut, LLC

Dec 2021 - Sep 2022

- Developed Python scripts to automate onboarding of new customers onto company MySQL database and HubSpot CRM.
- Developed Python scripts to speed onboarding of new locations for existing customers by cloning inventory data to the new store.
- Utilized Clover and HubSpot API's to maintain consistency between company database and these third-party services
- Served as point-of-contact for business partners, providing timely support with close collaboration with the development team

INDEPENDENT PROJECTS

more details available on my GitHub

Issue Tracker Web App

This fullstack project utilizes React, TypeScript, FastAPI, and SQLite; the backend is hosted on DigitalOcean. Features include creation, modification, and deletion of Issues. These Issues can be filtered using a search bar on the main page.

Order Processor Web Server

This backend project utilizes Express, TypeScript, Sequelize, and SQLite. Server features include validation of requests (JSend format) and formatting of currency data.

